Guide to the Bernhard Knollenberg Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence (Chronological), 1560-1943; Series I; 5.5 linear feet (13 Boxes)
  - ALS, Nathanael Greene to Jeremiah Wadsworth; loss of a child, wife and daughter ill; going to send a ship to carry tobacco from Virginia; financial affairs better, 1785 September 7 (Box 5, Folder 340)
  - ALS, Nathanael Greene to Jeremiah Wadsworth; need of a tutor to replace the one who just resigned, 1785 September 13 (Box 5, Folder 341)
  - ALS, Samuel Adams to [J. Adams]; fear of the Society of Cincinnatus, 1785 September 15 (Box 5, Folder 342)
  - Notice to all: Nathanael Greene for {symble}960-3-4 sold his interest in the Barnabas Dean & Co. stock to Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1785 September [9] (Box 5, Folder 343)
  - ALS, Nathanael Greene to Jeremiah Wadsworth; has found a tutor, a Mr. Miller of New Haven, and cancel previous request, 1785 October 1 (Box 5, Folder 344)
  - ALS, Nathanael Greene to Jeremiah Wadsworth; sending deed for his North River property for Wadsworth to sell; hopes to be able to pay debts with the profit from his crop, 1785 October 4 (Box 5, Folder 345)
  - ALS, Nathanael Greene to Jeremiah Wadsworth; Wadsworth's son and Mr. Miller arrived at the same time to be tutors; Greene finally decides on Miller, 1785 October 5 (Box 5, Folder 346)
  - Nathanael Greene appoints Jeremiah Wadsworth his true, sufficient and lawful attorney. Notice: Legal Document, 1785 October 11 (Box 5, Folder 347)
  - ALS, Augustus N. (?) to Mr. Clark; sign enclosed note. Saved for watermark by Knollenberg, 1786 February 2 (Box 5, Folder 349)
  - Retainer for Alexander Hamilton from the holders of the Spitzburg Patent holders, 1786 April 19 (Box 5, Folder 350)
  - ALS, Robert Morris to John Nicholson (comptroller of Penn.) refusing to get involved in a dispute between U.S. and Pennsylvania, 1786 July 20 (Box 5, Folder 351)
  - A letter to the Governor and Council of Maryland from Robert Smith to find out if it is legal to pay the interest on a purchased piece of property in certificate money or if only specie will be received, 1786 August 14 (Box 5, Folder 352)
  - ALS, William Burnet; Randal Hayes; Daniel Marsh to Mrs. Mary Ashfield; Mrs. Ashfield defrauded on a land deal, 1786 October 9 (Box 5, Folder 353)
  - ALS, Pierce Butler to Thomas Fitzsimons (merchant in Philadelphia); Butler has been defrauded in Holland; asks Fitzsimons to do him a favor, 1786 November 9 (Box 5, Folder 354)
  - A List of debts claimed in Pennsylvania against Benedict Arnold at the time of his treason.{symbol}398.2, (1786?) (Box 5, Folder 355)
  - Amount of the sales of the estates of Benedict Arnold forfeited to the State of Pennsylvania. {symbol}1547. 14. 9, 1786 (Box 5, Folder 356)
  - ALS, Alexander Hamilton to Robert Morris; approval of Declaration, 1786 (ca.) (Box 5, Folder 357)
  - ALS, Robert Morris to William Constable; invitation to stop in and asks him to mail some letters for France, 1787 April 24 (Box 5, Folder 358)
  - ALS, James Hillhouse to Dudley Woodbridge; a demand against Woodbridge was presented that was greater than his account, 1787 May 2 (Box 5, Folder 359)
  - ALS, Robert Morris to Mrs. Robert Morris; thanking for information obtained, 1787 July 20 (Box 5, Folder 360)
  - ALS, Joel Barlow to Abraham Baldwin; pick up balance owed Barlow by Ohio Company, 1787 October 16 (Box 5, Folder 361)
  - Receipt signed by William Tapp, Treasurer of the Ohio Co. for $9,848 40/90 from Joel Barlow, 1787 October 22 (Box 5, Folder 362)
  - List of certificates paid by Abiel Griswold in part of his share in the Ohio Co, 1787 October 22 (Box 5, Folder 363)
  - List of certificates paid by Abjah Cotton for one share in the Ohio Co, 1787 October 22 (Box 5, Folder 364)
  - List of certificates paid by John Watson for one share in the Ohio Co, 1787 October 22 (Box 5, Folder 365)
  - List of certificates paid by Nathan Whiting in part of his one share in the Ohio Co, 1787 October 22 (Box 5, Folder 366)
  - List of certificates paid to Samuel Wright in full for his share in the Ohio Co, 1787 October 22 (Box 5, Folder 367)
  - List of proprietors of Ohio Co. for whose shares Joel Barlow is accountable, [1787 Oct] (Box 5, Folder 368)
  - List of notes ent the treasurer of the Ohio Co. by Joel Barlow, [1787 Oct] (Box 5, Folder 369)
  - List of soldiers whose rights Joel Barlow has purchased, [1787 Oct] (Box 5, Folder 370)
  - ALS, Charles Thomson to the President of Congress explaining the 5th Article of Confederation, 1787 November 4 (Box 5, Folder 371)
  - ALS, James Gardoqui to George Washington; present of the latest Spanish edition of Don Quixote to the General, 1787 November 9 (Box 5, Folder 372)
  - Quit-Claim for $100 of 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. from Daniel Curtis to Joel Barlow, 1787 December 13 (Box 5, Folder 373)
  - ALS, Thomas Lord to Joel Barlow giving him power of attorney for 10 soldiers dealing with the Ohio Co, 1787 December 23 (Box 5, Folder 374)
  - Quit-Claim for $100 for 1/10 of I share of and in the Ohio Co. From Jesse Taylor to Joel Barlow, 1787 December 29 (Box 5, Folder 375)
  - ALS, Josiah Starr to Joel Barlow; concerns the Ohio Association and who owns what, 1788 January 16 (Box 5, Folder 376)
  - Mayor's Court New York, complaint of Cory Ludlow against John Leary for debt, 1788 February 5 (Box 5, Folder 377)
  - Quit-Claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Jeduthun Abby to Joel Barlow, 1788 February 6 (Box 5, Folder 378)
  - Quit-Claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Levi Risely to Joel Barlow, 1788 February 8 (Box 5, Folder 379)
  - Quit-Claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. John Lerou to Joel Barlow, 1788 February 13 (Box 5, Folder 380)
  - ALS, Admiral Auguste De Grasse to George Washington; Photostat, 1788 March 11 (Box 5, Folder 381)
  - Quit-Claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Israel Rowley to Joel Barlow, 1788 March 17 (Box 5, Folder 382)
  - Quit-Claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Moses; Griswold to Joel Barlow, 1788 March 18 (Box 5, Folder 383)
  - Quit-claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Thomas Wells to Joel Barlow, 1788 March 19 (Box 5, Folder 384)
  - Quit-claim for $200 for 1/5 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Thomas Anderson to Joel Barlow, 1788 March 19 (Box 5, Folder 385)
  - Account book of Joel Barlow as agent for the Ohio Land Co, 1788 March 20 (Box 5, Folder 386)
  - Quit-claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Giles Wilcox to Joel Barlow, 1788 April 3 (Box 5, Folder 387)
  - Quit-claim for for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. William Wease to Joel Barlow, 1788 April 8 (Box 5, Folder 388)
  - Quit-claim for for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Charles Reynolds to Joel Barlow, 1788 April 9 (Box 5, Folder 389)
  - Quit-claim for $3 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Matthew Ford to Joel Barlow, 1788 April 14 (Box 5, Folder 390)
  - Memorandum receipt of $950 from Mr. Wallam for I share of Ohio Co. stock, 1788 April 16 (Box 5, Folder 391)
  - Quit-claim for $3 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. John Reynolds to Joel Barlow, 1788 April 19 (Box 5, Folder 392)
  - Quit-claim for 20 shillings for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Peleg Heath to Joel Barlow, 1788 April 21 (Box 5, Folder 393)
  - Quit-claim for $3 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Jesse Harwood to Joel Barlow, 1788 April 23 (Box 5, Folder 394)
  - Quit-claim for $3 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Allen Corning to Joel Barlow, 1788 April 23 (Box 5, Folder 395)
  - Quit-claim for $100 for l/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Uriah Mead to Aaron Barlow, 1788 May 26 (Box 5, Folder 396)
  - Quit-claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Solomon Williams to Aaron Barlow, 1788 May 29 (Box 5, Folder 397)
  - Map of Township No. 6 in Range 15. In Ohio Co.?, (1788?) (Box 5, Folder 398)
  - ALS, Samuel Parker (Minister Trinity Church, Later PEC Bishop of Massachusetts) to Ebenezer Corey; pay to John Palmer 5-8-31, 1788 June 2 (Box 6, Folder 399)
  - ALS, Theodore Sedgwick to Alexander Hodgdon; has to get to Congress to ask for a 50 or 60 pound loan, 1788 July 1 (Box 6, Folder 400)
  - ALS, Mrs. Nathanael Greene to Jeremiah Wadsworth; things going well; asks Wadsworth to come down, 1788 December 24 (Box 6, Folder 401)
  - Quit-claim for $100 for 1/10 of 1 share of land in the Ohio Co. Luke Roberts to Aaron Barlow. Notice of receipt of money signed John Jay from R Robert Morris, 1789 February 28 (Box 6, Folder 402)
  - Notice of receipt of money signed John Jay from Robert Morris, 1789 March 10-December 24 (Box 6, Folder 403)
  - ALS, William Lee to Robert Carter inquring whether his vessel is to go to Baltimore, 1789 March 30 (Box 6, Folder 404)
  - Circular from Treasury Department: how to determine tonnage of vessels - Alexander Hamilton, 1789 December 23 (Box 6, Folder 405)
  - ADS, Steubening; Record of money paid and owed (French), 1790 January 1 (Box 6, Folder 406)
  - Receipt of two bonds from Janet Probasco for {symble} 196.1.1 and {symble} 27.16.3 Frederick Frelinghuysen, 1790 February 26 (Box 6, Folder 407)
  - Pay to the order of Benjamin Clinch {symble}15 signed Peter Gansvoort, 1790 March 6 (Box 6, Folder 408)
  - ALS, George Washington to Beverly Randolph; thank you for. information concerning the Western country. Photostat of Original, 1790 June 14 (Box 6, Folder 409)
  - ALS, (Draft) Samuel Huntington to Oliver Ellsworth; Jonathan Trumbull and other notifying them of their election to Congress, 1790 October 23 (Box 6, Folder 410)
  - ALS, Stephen Higginson to Messers. Le Roy and Bayard; congratulating them at forming a new firm. Most of letter deals with business transactions pending, 1790 November 30 (Box 6, Folder 411)
  - ALS, Philip Schuyler to (?); drinking wine despite orders not to; complains of the hot weather, 1791 July 27 (Box 6, Folder 412)
  - ALS, General Knox to Samuel Hodgdon (Quarter Master) troops should move into the Ohio, 1791 August 4 (Box 6, Folder 413)
  - ALS, William Duer to Benjamin Walker, procurement of supplies for troops, 1791 October 25 (Box 6, Folder 414)
  - ALS, Christopher P. Yates (able lawyer; member of Congress) to Abraham Hun; need to post notice of a matter referred to in previous letter, 1792 October 4 (Box 6, Folder 415)
  - ALS, Christopher Gore (Governor of Massachusetts) to Samuel Russell Gerry (Collector of Port Marble head); Gerry must enforce the laws of the U.S, 1793 March 6 (Box 6, Folder 416)
  - Envelope addressed to Robert Morris by Alexander Hamilton, 1793 March 30 (Box 6, Folder 417)
  - Memorandum by Henry Lee of a transfer to W.A. Washington of ... a judgement ... against Peter Conway, 1793 April 19 (Box 6, Folder 417A)
  - Notice to Sheriff of Queens County of N.Y. to take James Smith, signed by Mr. Nesson, 1793 May 4 (Box 6, Folder 418)
  - ALS, General Knox to Samuel Hodgdon; order to supply clothes to the troops of a Lt. Thompson, 1793 November 14 (Box 6, Folder 419)
  - ALS, General Knox to Samuel Hodgdon; to provide clothing for the 95 men under Lt. Richards, 1793 December 27 (Box 6, Folder 421)
  - AL, Alexander Hamilton to John Ball; instructions on bow to pay $400,000 loan, 1793 December 28 (Box 6, Folder 422)
  - ALS, Edward Livingston to (?) enclosing a list of bonds left in the hands of Matthew(?) Visscher; plus discussion of various legal matters, 1794 February 6 (Box 6, Folder 423)
  - ALS, General Henry Knox to General Jackson urging "no war by the Grace of God", 1794 March 29 (Box 6, Folder 424)
  - ALS, Daniel Howell (Member of Congress) to (?); concerns the case of Benjamin Weeden to the court of common pleas, 1794 May undated (Box 6, Folder 426)
  - Envelope signed Edward Randolph to (Robert) Morris, 1794 August 14 (Box 6, Folder 427)
  - ALS, Theodore Sedgwick to Justin Ely; concerns Congressional elections in Massachusetts, 1794 December 9 (Box 6, Folder 430)
  - ALS, Alexander Hamilton to the President of the Bank of the United States, 1794 December 26 (Box 6, Folder 431)
  - Receipt for rations received at Fort Randolph signed David Jones, Chaplain, 1795 May 27 (Box 6, Folder 432)
  - ALS, James Dana to Reverend Doctor Lathrop; introducing Mr. Atwater who wants to study for the ministry; regrets the death of President Stiles, 1795 June 4 (Box 6, Folder 433)
  - ALS, Nathaniel Niles to (?); asks his friend to help him think through some moral questions, 1795 June 5 (Box 6, Folder 434)
  - Notice from Governor William Blount Of Ohio to David Henley, to pay William Richard, paymaster, $1,398. 95 for the payment of troops. Photostat of Original, 1795 July 1 (Box 6, Folder 435)
  - Notice from Governor William Bount to David Henley (agent with the War Dept.) to pay William Richard $298 to pay troops with. Photostat of Original, 1795 July 10 (Box 6, Folder 436)
  - ALS, Tench Coxe to William Paterson (member of U.S. Supreme Court); tells Paterson he has suggested him for the post of Secretary of State, 1795 August 27 (Box 6, Folder 437)
  - Return of rations to commissary acknowledged William Henry Harrison (later President of the U.S.), 1795 August 29 (Box 6, Folder 438)
  - ALS, Jonathan Dayton to Robert Morris; information on a bond was given to Mr. Boggs who then left town, 1796 January 12 (Box 6, Folder 439)
  - ALS, Robert Morris to Joshua Highee; asks for the return of a certificate for share of stock, 1796 March 12 (Box 6, Folder 440)
  - ALS, Henry Knox to Mr. Bingham; concerns the refusal of Georgia to muster militia for a campaign against the Indians, 1796 March 21 (Box 6, Folder 441)
  - ALS, Horatio Gates to Patrick Carson; rumbling about the speculators in land; had nothing to do with stock in Landjobbing, 1796 March 22 (Box 6, Folder 442)
  - ALS, Jonathan Dayton to Robert Morris; inquiring when Morris will be home so that he can collect an $1100 debt, 1796 June 13 (Box 6, Folder 443)
  - ALS, Henry Knox to Samuel Hodgdon; concerning the payment and distribution of cargo from the schooner Friendship, 1796 July 8 (Box 6, Folder 445)
  - ALS, Jared Ingersoll to William Arnold; requesting fees for case argued and lost by Ingersoll, 1796 September 6 (Box 6, Folder 446)
  - ALS, Silas Dinsmoore (Indian Agent) to David Henley (War Dept. agent); discusses the problems of the Indians and their relationship to the white settlers, 1797 January 8 (Box 16)
  - ALS, John Marshall to Henry Bedinger, will take up Bedinger's case and try to collect debt for him, 1797 January 29 (Box 6, Folder 448)
  - ALS, John Beatty to Dayton regarding proposed land tax in New Jersey, the Milition Bill, State Legislature. Trenton, 1797 February 24 (Box 6, Folder 449)
  - ALS, William Puffin to Quartermaster and request for corn to feed cattle for U.S. Army. Washington, 1797 April 9 (Box 6, Folder 450)
  - TLS, Thomas Paine to George Washington; severe criticism of American foreign policy and Washington himself. Photostat of excerpt from typed copy. London, 1797 (Box 6, Folder 454)
  - ALS, John Bayard to Robert Morris; regarding draft of $320 of James Boggs by Morris for purchase of bill of exchange of Rich, Penn, 1798 January 20 (Box 6, Folder 455)
  - Certificate of Indenture between Anthony Abeel and Abraham Cortely, 1798 March 1 (Box 16)
  - ALS, John Hasing to Robert Morris; regarding law transactions with Morris as attorney for Mr. Penn, 1798 March 17 (Box 6, Folder 457)
  - DS, James Garrard (Governor of Kentucky) to Joseph Boswell-appointment as surgeon's mate of 8th regiment of militia, 1799 May 20 (Box 6, Folder 459)
  - ALS, Winthrop [?] to [?]; request for contract to be given to Mr. [Hontz], 1799 May 26 (Box 6, Folder 460)
  - ALS, Wolcott (Treasury Dept.) to Jonathan Rhea regarding compensations to assessors instates, 1799 May 31 (Box 6, Folder 461)
  - ALS, Paul Revere to Silas Talbot (commander of U.S. Constitution);recommendation of young man to serve as midshipman, 1799 June 5 (Box 6, Folder 462)
  - ALS, Aaron Ogden (Gov. of New Jersey) to Lt. William Anderson regarding military appointment. Elizabeth, 1799 June 14 (Box 6, Folder 463)
  - ALS, General Frelinghousen to Gov. Robert Morris; regret for hearing at Trenton, 1799 September 11 (Box 6, Folder 464)
  - ADS, Deed between Daniel Kipsam (attorney, N.Y.) and John B. Kipsam (N.Y.) regarding title of farm, 1800 June 12 (Box 6, Folder 466)
  - ANS, General Rufus Putnam regarding Joel Barlow and Ohio Company, 1800 August 5 (Box 6, Folder 468)
  - ALS, William Hull (Mass.) to James Madison (Secretary of State); recommendation of John Rogers as counsel for Valencia, 1801 August 12 (Box 6, Folder 470)
  - ADS, John Smith (Sheriff of Pickering County); warrant for larceny. Mississippi Territory, 1801 December 13 (Box 6, Folder 471)
  - ALS, James Sullivan to William Curtis, Esq. - long letter about John Adams' tendency toward aristocracy and general views on the Union, 1802 January 13 (Box 6, Folder 473)
  - ALS, Alex Walcott to Henry Van Schaack, Esq. regarding authorization to interrogate, some discussion of possibility of matching up Van Schaack's nephew and Walcott's daughter, 1802 August 28 (Box 6, Folder 476)
  - ADS, Joel Barlow to Directors of Ohio Co.- appointment of nephews to represent him in dealings with Company, 1802 September 7 (Box 6, Folder 477)
  - ALS, Benjamin Tallmadge to Stephen Barlow, Esq. regarding Ohio Company's directions to stop dividends. Recommends writing to Rufus Putnam, 1802 December 21 (Box 6, Folder 478)
  - ALS, Mother to Mary Hillhouse regarding various matters including yellow fever epidemic, quarantines, 1803 August 2 (Box 6, Folder 479)
  - ADS, Skinner (tax collector); Receipt for Joel Barlow for land tax, 1803 October 3 (Box 6, Folder 480)
  - DS, Transfer certificate from Ohio Company to Joel Barlow, 1803 October 4 (Box 16)
  - ALS, Benjamin Tallmadge to W. Barlow regarding dividends on Ohio Co. land, 1803 November 22 (Box 6, Folder 482)
  - ADS, Jacob Drayton regarding General Nathanael Greene and all judgements and suits against him, 1804 January 15 (Box 6, Folder 483)
  - ADS, List of materials ? Col. William L. Smith, 1804 August 27 (Box 16)
  - ADS, Augustus John Foster (English Sec. of delegation to United States) appointment of Charles Broughton as his counsel, 1804 September 28 (Box 6, Folder 485)
  - ALS, Daniel Clymer to Pierpont Edwards regarding Gov. Morris and family affairs. Photostat, 1804 November 20 (Box 6, Folder 487)
  - ALS, Lindley Murry to Alice (?), Photostat, 1805 February 6 (Box 6, Folder 488)
  - ALS, J.W. Edwards to Joel Barlow regarding payment owed to Ohio Company, 1805 October 22 (Box 6, Folder 489)
  - ALS, Nathan Sanford to Samuel M. Hopkins; Hopkins' clients are instructed to pay $6943.50 for suit against them, 1805 October 23 (Box 6, Folder 490)
  - ALS, P.B. Partis (?) to Samuel M. Hopkins (attorney) regarding failure of payment of debts, 1805 December 8 (Box 6, Folder 491)
  - AD, Receipt of $51 paid by Joel Barlow at hands of Alexander Wolcott, 1806 January 7 (Box 6, Folder 492)
  - ALS, Benjamin Tallmadge to Joel Barlow regarding Ohio Company land, 1806 February 11 (Box 6, Folder 493)
  - ALS, M.G. Schuneman to Bagandus Flans concerning land in Natchis, 1806 February 25 (Box 6, Folder 494)
  - PDS, Caleb Strong (Gov. of Mass.) to John Griggs; appointment as ensign in Mass. Militia, 1806 April 14 (Box 6, Folder 495)
  - ALS, John Adams (President) to Benjamin Rush (Philadelphia); mentions Franklin, Jefferson possible war involvement, 1806 September 19 (Box 6, Folder 496)
  - ALS, Le Major General (unidentified) to General of Division Laison; letter in French, 1806 October 23 (Box 6, Folder 497)
  - ALS, fragment from Simon Kenton, 1806 (Box 6, Folder 498)
  - ADS, Capt. Basil Wood (19th Reg, Virg. Militia), detailing return of his company and number of arms held, 1807 March 10 (Box 6, Folder 500)
  - ADS, Joel Barlow to William Wells, receipt for taxes, 1809 February 4 (Box 6, Folder 501)
  - ALS, G.H. Hobart to Col Elias B. Dayton, regarding purchase of land and house, 1809 March 12 (Box 6, Folder 502)
  - ADS, Shimson (?) tax collector; receipt for taxes from Joel Barlow, 1810 December 15 (Box 6, Folder 503)
  - ALS, Josiah Whitney to Rev. Joseph Lathrop; Inquiry for new candidate to replace Whitney, 1811 January 11 (Box 6, Folder 504)
  - ADS, Shimson (?), tax collector, receipt for taxes from Stephen Barlow, 1811 November 4 (Box 6, Folder 505)
  - ADS, Ebenezer Granger (tax collector); receipt for taxes on Ohio land from Stephen Barlow, 1811 November 19 (Box 6, Folder 506)
  - ALS, Leonard Woods to Rev. R.S. Storrs; requests Storrs to go to Assembly as Wood's alternate, 1812 March 14 (Box 6, Folder 507)
  - ALS, John Quincy Adams to Joel Barlow, regarding conflict between Russia, England and Sweden, 1812 June 2 (Box 6, Folder 508)
  - ALS, Eli Whitney to (?) regarding financial matters, 1812 August 8 (Box 6, Folder 509)
  - ALS, Erick Bollmann to Jonathan Dayton; request for man to man crucibles, 1812 December 9 (Box 6, Folder 510)
  - ADS, James Perry (tax collector); receipt for taxes of Joel Barlow, 1812 December 23 (Box 6, Folder 511)
  - ALS, Martin Van Buren (?)to E. Throop Middle District Votes, 1813 April 20 (Box 6, Folder 512)
  - ADS, S.P. Hildreth (collector of non-resident tax) receipt for taxes from Stephen Barlow, 1813 October 30 (Box 6, Folder 513)
  - ALS, Gov. Smith of Conn. to Gen. Brubert informing him that guards are ordered out, 1813 October 30 (Box 6, Folder 514)
  - ALS, Rev. Elijah Parish to Rev. D. McClure (brother) concerning sermons, papers, etc, 1813 November 18 (Box 6, Folder 515)
  - ADS, James Perry (tax collector); receipt for taxes from Joel Barlow, 1813 December 22 (Box 6, Folder 516)
  - ALS, Abraham Abott to Jacob Perkins; relates battles with British. With typed copy, 1814 January 18 (Box 7, Folder 517)
  - ALS, Bureau to (unidentified); Enclosure for transfer of deed, 1814 January 10 (Box 7, Folder 518)
  - ALS, Elizabeth Lyon to Mrs. Emilia Bennett (sisters) regarding family affairs, sisters' return to visit, 1814 March 21 (Box 7, Folder 519)
  - ALS, W. Seth Hunt to Augustine Prevost; inquiry, about sale of land in West Florida, 1814 April 9 (Box 7, Folder 520)
  - ADS, Lt. Gen. John Doyle to John Glack (Deputy Paymaster General); authorization to draw bills, 1814 April 23 (Box 7, Folder 521)
  - ALS, Ely Swan to Steven Colt (Merchant) regarding price of groceries, liquour, 1814 September 17 (Box 7, Folder 522)
  - ADS, A. G. Coombs (Major, 2nd Batt.) to Capt. Elhanan Spear-organization of two companies, 1814 September 30 (Box 7, Folder 523)
  - ADS, James Perry (tax collector); receipt for taxes from Joel Barlow, 1814 December 10 (Box 7, Folder 524)
  - ADS, J.P. Heldreth (tax collector); receipt for taxes from Stephen Barlow, 1814 December 20 (Box 7, Folder 525)
  - ALS, Benjamin Tallmadge to President of United States; request for commission in Navy for Tallmadge's son, 1815 January (Box 7, Folder 526)
  - ALS, Col. Thomas Jesup to Col.Thomas Aspinwall (consul at London); letter of introduction, 1815 October 11 (Box 7, Folder 527)
  - ADS, James Perry (tax collector); receipt for taxes from Joel Barlow, 1815 December 27, 1816 December 30, 1817 December 2 (Box 7, Folder 528-530)
  - ALS, John C. Calhoun to Hon. John Crowell (House of Representatives); refusal to help change court decision on deserter, 1818 January 4 (Box 7, Folder 531)
  - DS, Cadwanader D. Golden (Mayor of New York); Freedom paper for Negro Slave, James Coles, 1818 May 13 (Box 7, Folder 532)
  - ALS, (?) to R. Donnell regarding counterfeit note of $50, 1818 August 24 (Box 7, Folder 533)
  - ALS, John Bell to Aaron White regarding family and business matters. Photostat of Original, 1818 September 25 (Box 7, Folder 534)